So, it's exam time again — have you done the necessary work to get good marks?
所以，又到考试时间了——你有没有为取得好成绩做必要的准备呢？
Sleeping with the textbook under the pillow in the hope that knowledge will be magically absorbed into your brain as you sleep doesn't work.
把课本放在枕头底下睡觉，指望睡觉时知识能神奇地被大脑吸收，这是行不通的。
The best strategy is to space your practice out, rather than cram it all together.
最好的策略是把你的学习时间分散开，而不是把所有的学习任务都集中在一起。
It means hit the books early!
这意味着要早点开始用功读书！
In an article in the British newspaper The Guardian, Tom Stafford, a lecturer in psychology and cognitive science at the University of Sheffield, UK, advises: "If you organise five hours of study into one hour a day, you'll remember more than if you study for five hours on one day."
在英国《卫报》的一篇文章中，英国谢菲尔德大学心理学和认知科学讲师汤姆·斯塔福德建议道：“如果你把五个小时的学习时间安排成每天一小时，那么你记住的内容会比一天学习五个小时记住的更多。”
Don't rely on memory alone — get pen and paper and start working.
不要仅仅依赖记忆——拿出笔和纸，开始学习吧。
Students who can test themselves in advance will be better at retrieving material from their memory and learn that material in the long run.
能够提前自我测试的学生将更善于从记忆中检索信息，并且从长远来看，他们能更好地掌握这些知识。
John Dunlosky, Professor of Psychology at Kent State University in the US, suggests that "you start by reading a textbook using your favourite highlighter and favourite colours, but then you go back and make flashcards of all the critical concepts and instead of just rereading those, you basically try to test yourselves on them."
美国肯特州立大学心理学教授约翰·邓洛斯基建议：“你可以先用你最喜欢的荧光笔和喜欢的颜色阅读课本，然后回过头来，把所有关键概念做成抽认卡，不要只是重读这些概念，而要从根本上尝试对自己进行测试。”
Good revision should give you confidence, but if you are still anxious, there's no harm in indulging in a personal ritual.
良好的复习应该能给你信心，但如果你仍然感到焦虑，沉迷于个人仪式也无妨。
In Japan, it seems to be a tradition for students to eat Katsudon before a test.
在日本，学生们在考试前吃猪排盖饭似乎是一种传统。
This is a warm bowl of rice topped with egg and a deep-fried pork cutlet.
这是一碗热腾腾的米饭，上面盖着鸡蛋和炸猪排。
The name of the dish reminds people of the word 'katsu', meaning 'winning'.
这道菜的名字让人联想到“katsu”这个词，意思是“胜利”。
For some students in South Korea, the key to success is not washing their hair before sitting an exam because they believe they could wash all the knowledge out of their head.
对于一些韩国学生来说，成功的关键是在参加考试前不洗头，因为他们认为洗头会把脑子里的知识都洗掉。
And in different parts of the world there are always those who swear by their 'lucky underwear'.
而且在世界的不同地方，总是有人对他们的“幸运内裤”深信不疑。
The bottom line is that you need to study, sleep well on the eve of the test, eat a nutritious meal, drink plenty of water and believe that your efforts will pay off.
最重要是你需要学习，在考试前夕睡个好觉，吃一顿有营养的饭，多喝水，并且相信你的努力会有回报。
Good luck in your exam!
祝你考试好运！